The examples of code you see in this course
are short, simple code snippets used either
alone or as part of a larger, more robust
program. Code, or the purpose of code written,
should be understandable, even to people
unfamiliar with the intent of the code.
Comments are text that follows the number symbol,
either on a line by itself or at the end of a
line of code. Python will ignore this text during
execution, allowing you to annotate your code for
better understanding. I have this 413-comments
file open and will add a comment on line 4,
above the while loop, explaining what the
while loop does. These explanations can
help one remember what code is supposed to
do, which can help build proper game flows,
and comments can help others understand the
purpose of code. Comments can also be inline,
meaning they can be placed to the right of a
line, and anything after the comment is ignored.
Comments do not split lines, however, so each
line can only have one inline comment. I will
add a comment to the end of line 6 explaining why
we need to set the range to 11 when the loop runs
10 times. Finally, and this is something
we have seen in the course, a comment can
comment out a code statement or line of code,
meaning that the code is legitimate but needs
to be ignored temporarily. Lines are commented
out when developers want to test blocks of code
with minimal distractions and thus pinpoint
potential problems more easily. For example,
the print statement on line 10 is unnecessary for
testing this code. Therefore, I will add a number
symbol in front of the code on line 10, run this
code, and the code executes but does not print the
thank you statement on line 10 as it has been
commented out. Python doesn't natively support
block comments, multi-line comments, like
some other languages, but in the next topic,
we will see how we can get the equivalent of a
multi-line comment through the use of docstrings.